AMOL PANDYA

HR Manager

□ amolpandya@gmail.com

9909368946

Nirnaynagar, Ahmedabad, India

in https://www.linkedin.com/in/amol-p-8b7568215/



Profile

As an experienced HR professional, I excel in cultivating relationships with diverse individuals and groups, and have top-notch communication and interpersonal skills. I have expertise in HR database management, hiring protocols, recruitment strategies, interviewing techniques, engaging and retaining employees, negotiating, mediating conflicts, developing staff, implementing HR policies, and managing benefits and compensation. With a successful track record of achieving organizational goals through effective HR management, I am an unparalleled candidate for any HR position.

Professional Experience

Healthark Wellness Solutions LLP, HR Manager ₽

05/2021 - present | Ahmedabad, India

- Collaborate with business leaders to understand their strategic objectives and develop HR strategies that support those goals.
- Analyze workforce trends and proactively identify areas for improvement in talent management, performance, and organizational effectiveness.
- Develop, implement, and manage human resources policies, programs, and initiatives that align with the company's goals and strategies.
- Manage recruitment and hiring processes, including creating job descriptions, posting job ads, screening resumes, interviewing candidates, and making job offers.
- Manage employee relations, including addressing grievances, managing conflicts, and resolving issues between employees or between employees and management.
- Develop and implement performance management processes, including goal setting, performance reviews, and performance improvement plans. Provide guidance and support to managers on effectively managing employee performance and development.
- Collect and analyze HR data to identify trends, patterns, and areas for improvement. Prepare and present reports to management, providing insights and recommendations based on HR analytics.
- Develop and implement programs to foster a positive and inclusive work environment. Conduct employee surveys, analyze results, and develop action plans to improve employee engagement and satisfaction.
- Develop and manage employee training programs to ensure that new hires are quickly integrated into the company culture and equipped to perform their roles effectively.
- Ensure legal and regulatory compliance with employment laws and regulations, including equal opportunity regulations, labor laws, and health and safety standards.

Endeavor Careers Pvt. Ltd, HR Manager ⊗

02/2018 - 12/2020 | Ahmedabad, India

- Talent acquisition involves managing the recruitment cycle for executive to senior-level positions, using various cost-effective and talent-aligned hiring channels. This includes maintaining a recruitment tracker and partnering with the business to identify their requirements. Facilitating interviews and talent assessments is also a key responsibility.
- On-boarding new employees involves conducting induction programs, verifying documents, and creating HRIS profiles for a smooth transition.
- Employee relations and operations entail coordinating employee engagement activities, updating
 employee data records, and being the HR point of contact for employee grievances and process
 compliance.
- Training and performance management involve planning the yearly training calendar, coordinating the training process, and evaluating its effectiveness. This also includes liaising for annual appraisals and collecting 360-degree feedback data from internal and external stakeholders.

Universal Hunt - ARC Consultant, Team Manager ∂

- 12/2014 11/2017 | Ahmedabad, India
- Manage the entire recruitment cycle, including candidate attraction, shortlisting, and initial screening for the executive
- to senior-level requisitions.
- Utilize cost-effective and talent-aligned hiring channels, such as online job portals, employee referrals, in-house
- databases, networks, and social media to attract candidates.
- Maintain an Applicant Tracking System (ATS) to track and manage candidates throughout the recruitment process.
- Work closely with business leaders to identify their hiring needs and ensure timely delivery of qualified candidates.
- Facilitate interviews and talent assessments, and conduct candidate screenings, testing, and assessments.
- Arrange interviews with shortlisted candidates and negotiate salaries between clients and candidates.
- Coordinate with clients to ensure timely delivery and feedback on candidates.
- Manage a team of up to five members, demonstrating leadership and collaboration skills.

Medusind Solution, Executive *⊘*

11/2013 - 12/2014 | Ahmedabad, India

- Conducted comprehensive eligibility and verification checks for patients with exceptional accuracy and timeliness. Formulated and dispatched professional follow-up emails to clients, guaranteeing transparent communication and prompt resolution of any outstanding concerns.
- Fostered effective communication with healthcare providers by placing outbound calls to the USA, utilizing exceptional telephone etiquette and active listening skills.

Education

PGDBM, Lyceum Academy (United Kingdom)

05/2012 | Edgeware, United Kingdom

B Com, Gujarat University

10/2009 | Ahmedabad, India

Higher secondary certificate, Gujarat Board

03/2006 | Vadodara, India

Languages

Gujarati

• • • • •

Hindi

 \bullet

English

 \bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet

Awards

Rising Star, Director

03/2016

• I have been awarded as Rising Star in the year 2015-16 for achieving the highest revenue.

Centurion Award, Director

03/2016

• I have received a centurion award for placing the highest number of candidates.

Muster Master Award. Director

03/2016

• Also have received an award of Muster Master of the year 2015-16.by attending 96.60% presence during the year.

Certificates

- Human Resource Management ∂
- Advancing Your Skills as an HR Business Partner ∂
- Conflict Management ∂

Al Tools ∂

- A TO Z Of POSH ACT ∂
- The Data Science of Using People Analytics ∂
- \bullet ChatGPT For HR ${\mathscr Q}$

Interests

• Listening To Music

Swimming

Bowling

Movies